Preliminary Inventory to the Gustavus T. Kirby Papers, 1914-1941
Hoover Institution Archives
Gustavus T. Kirby Papers,
1914-1941
56026
Kirby, Gustavus T.
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, correspondence, clippings, map, and card file, relating to relief in Belgium during World Wars I and II, exchange of Belgian and American Fellows through the C.R.B. Educational Foundation, and charitable and goodwill efforts of the Friends of Belgium.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Biographical/Historical Note
Member, Executive Committee, Friends of Belgium.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, correspondence, clippings, map, and card file, relating to relief in Belgium during World Wars I and II, exchange of Belgian and American Fellows through the C.R.B. Educational Foundation, and charitable and goodwill efforts of the Friends of Belgium.
Access Points
C.R.B. Educational Foundation, inc.; Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); Commission for Relief in Belgium (1940-1945); Friends of Belgium.; Education.; International relief.; Scholarships--Belgium.; Scholarships--United States.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Belgium.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Belgium.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; Belgium.; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Osterberg, Anne, 1923 December 26
  - Weber, Orlando F., 1936 July 1
- World War II Belgian relief (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Wood, L. H., 1940 July 30
    - Galpin, Perrin C., 1940 July 26, August 1
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Hoover and Relief to Belgium
  - Press Release regarding Relief in Europe, 1940 July 24
  - Food map prepared by the Commission for Relief in Belgium
- Belgian medals (2) One large and one small impression of the same medal, "from Belgium to the U.S. in gratitude for the generosity shown" (Folder 3)
- Index cards listing Relief Organization Members and showing foreign decorations awarded (Folder 4)
- Photographs; photograph of major? (Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous materials (Folder 6)
  - Pamphlet, The Legend of the "Francs-Tireurs" of Louvain, E. L. Thompson, 1928
  - Pamphlet, The Belgian Campaign and the Surrender of the Belgian Army, 1940 May 10-28
  - Pamphlet, Statistical Review of the Economic and Technological Development of the U.S., 1800-1930, 1935 May 14
  - Pamphlet, Remarks made by Major Leon Osterrieth, Military Attaché, Chief of the Belgian Military Mission to the United States of America, on the occasion of the Belgian Armoured Motor Corps across the United States
  - Pamphlet, Belgium, Vol. 1, No. 2, 1941
- Friends of Belgium materials (Folder 7)
- Flour sack, Painted (Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Folder 9)
- Commission for Relief in Belgium Foundation, Inc. (Folder 10)
  - Preliminary reports of Belgian Fellows in the United States
    - 1931-32
    - 1932-33
  - Final reports of American Fellows in Belgium
    - 1932-33
  - Final reports of Belgian Fellows in the United States (Folder 11)
    - 1932-33
    - 1933-34
    - 1934-35
  - Final reports of American Fellows in Belgium
    - 1933-34
    - 1934-35
  - Preliminary reports of Belgian fellows in the United States (Folder 12)
    - 1934-35
    - 1936-37
  - Final reports of American fellows in Belgium
    - 1935-36
  - Preliminary reports of American fellows in Belgium
    - 1934-35
    - 1936-37
  - Stated Meeting of Members and Directors, 1936 December 1
  - Final reports of Belgian Fellows in the United States (Folder 13)
    - 1936-37
  - Final reports of American Fellows in Belgium
    - 1936-37
  - Reports of CRB summer stipend holders who attended the courses in Flemish Art and Modern Belgian Art held in Brussels, Belgium, 1937 July 7-August 12
  - Final reports of CRB American advanced fellows visiting scientist in Belgium
    - 1937-38
  - Preliminary reports of CRB American fellows in Belgium
    - 1937-38
  - Reports of CRB summer stipend holders who attended the courses in Flemish Art and Modern Belgian Art held in Brussels, Belgium (Folder 14)
    - 1938 July 11-August 14
    - 1939 July 17-August 26 Third Year
  - Preliminary reports of American visiting lecturers advanced fellows grants-in-aid in Belgium, 1938-39
  - Preliminary and final reports of CRB American advanced fellows, grants-in-aid in Belgium, 1939-40
  - Preliminary reports of Belgian advanced fellows Graduate Students in the United States, 1938-39
  - Preliminary and final reports of CRB Belgian visiting scientists, advanced fellows, Graduate Students in the United States, 1939-40
- Mounted photo of statue of Edith Cavell (Box 2)